Guide to the Charles Abrams papers, 1923-1970.
Abrams, Charles papers, 1923-1970
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Charles Abrams papers, 1923-1970.
3086
Charles Abrams 1902-1970.
128 Cubic Feet., 54 reels positive microfilm
Correspondence, manuscripts, clippings, scrapbooks, microfilm
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Papers include biographical materials, speeches, course materials, lectures, newspaper clippings, press releases, and correspondence pertaining to organizations and agencies in which Abrams was actively involved.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Lawyer, urban housing planner, professor of city planning.
Charles Abrams studied at Brooklyn Law School, and was a landlord in Greenwich Village. He became an authority on urban housing, and served as a consultant on various private, state, federal, and international housing projects. He taught city planning at several colleges, and wrote numerous books, articles, and pamphlets on housing, planning, racial problems, neighborhoods, and other aspects of urban life.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Papers include biographical materials, speeches, course materials, lectures, newspaper clippings, press releases, and correspondence with Max Bloom, John Clarke, Aryeh Cooperstock, Jacob Crane, Alexander L. Crosby, Earle S. Draper, Julius Edelstein, Felix Frankfurter, Josephine Gomon, William L. Halford, Averell Harriman, Hubert H. Humphrey, Jacob K. Javits, J. Marshall Kaplan, John F. Kennedy, Robert F. Kennedy, Blanche Mahler Koeffler, Otto Koenigsberger, Louis J. Lefkowitz, Herbert Lehman, Max Lerner, John V. Lindsay, Lewis Lorwin, Bleecker Marquette, Albert Mayer, Morris Miller, Constance Baker Motley, Daniel Patrick Moynihan, Kevin Nowlan, William S. Paley, Charles H. Percy, Langdon Post, Perry Prentice, A. Philip Randolph, Lloyd Rodwin, Arthur M. Schlesinger, Jr., Nathan Straus, Walter Thabit, Jacqueline Tyrwhitt, Warren Jay Vinton, Robert F. Wagner, Jr., William English Walling, Harrison A. Williams, Herman Wouk, and Catherine Bauer Wurster pertaining to organizations and agencies in which Abrams was actively involved, including the Agency for International Development, American Federation of Housing Authorities, American Institute of Architects, American Institute of Planners, American Jewish Congress, Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith, Department of Housing and Urban Development, Ekistico-Delos, Federal Public Housing Authority, Ford Foundation, and the Housing and Home Finance Agency.
Correspondence also concerns the International Federation for Housing and Town Planning, National Association for the Advancement of Colored People, National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing, National Committee on the Housing Emergency, National Public Housing Conference, New York State Commission Against Discrimination, Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group; Abrams' affiliations with Columbia University, Harvard University, Massachusetts Institute of Technology, New School for Social Research, Princeton University, United Nations International School, and the University of Pennsylvania. There are studies pertaining to Abrams' principal work in planning domestic and foreign housing, prepared while on United Nations missions to Kenya, Pakistan, India, the Philippines, Ireland, Japan, Jamaica, Singapore, and other places. Also available are published and unpublished articles on housing and a list of articles written by Abrams while affiliated with the NEW YORK POST; drafts, galley notes, and reviews of "Housing Programs for America," and "Squatter Settlements"; a manuscript for "The City is the Frontier"; and unfinished manuscripts for "Democracy in Crisis," and "Housing for the People." Also, family correspondence and personal financial materials.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Abrams, Charles,1902-1970.; Bloom, Max.; Clarke, John.; Cooperstock, Aryeh.; Crane, Jacob L.(Jacob Leslie), 1892-1988.; Crosby, Alexander L.; Draper, Earle Sumner, 1893-; Edelstein, Julius.; Frankfurter, Felix, 1882-1965.; Gomon, Josephine.; Halford, William L.; Harriman, W. Averell(William Averell), 1891-; Humphrey, Hubert H.(Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978.; Javits, Jacob K.(Jacob Koppel), 1904-; Kaplan, J. Marshall.; Kennedy, John F.(John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963.; Kennedy, Robert F., 1925-1968.; Koeffler, Blanche Mahler.; Koenigsberger, Otto H.; Lefkowitz, Louis J.; Lehman, Herbert H.(Herbert Henry), 1878-1963.; Lerner, Max, 1902-; Lindsay, John V.(John Vliet); Lorwin, Lewis Levitski, 1883-1970.; Marquette, Bleecker.; Mayer, Albert.; Miller, Morris.; Motley, Constance Baker, 1921-; Moynihan, Daniel P.(Daniel Patrick), 1927-; Nowlan, Kevin B.; Paley, William S.(William Samuel), 1901-; Percy, Charles H., 1919-; Post, Langdon.; Prentice, Perry.; Randolph, A. Philip(Asa Philip), 1889-; Rodwin, Lloyd.; Schlesinger, Arthur Meier, 1917-; Straus, Nathan.; Thabit, Walter.; Tyrwhitt, Jacqueline.; Vinton, Warren Jay, 1889-1969.; Wagner, Robert Ferdinand, 1910-; Walling, William, 1926-; Wouk, Herman, 1915-; Wurster, Catherine Bauer; American Federation of Housing Authorities.; American Institute of Architects.; American Institute of Planners.; American Jewish Congress.; B'nai B'rith.Anti-Defamation League.; Columbia University--Faculty.; Ekistico-Delos.; Ford Foundation.; Harvard University--Faculty.; International Federation for Housing and Town Planning.; Massachusetts Institute of Technology--Faculty.; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People.; National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing.; National Committee on the Housing Emergency (U.S.); National Public Housing Conference.; New School for Social Research.; New York (State).Temporary Commission Against Discrimination.; Southeast Asia Development Advisory Group.; United Nations.; United States.Agency for International Development.; United States.Federal Public Housing Authority.; United States.Housing and Home Finance Agency.; University of Pennsylvania--Faculty.
Titles:
New York post.
Subjects:
City planning.; Discrimination in housing.; Housing.; Land use, Urban.; Urban policy.; Urban renewal.; Housing--India.; Housing--Ireland.; Housing--Kenya.; Housing--Pakistan.; Housing--Philippines.; Housing--Singapore.
Form and Genre Terms:
Lectures.; Speeches.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Reel 54: photoduplication and distribution not permitted.
The published guide, containing more information about the collection, is available by clicking here. 1.5 MB PDF
The microfilm reel and frame guide is available by clicking here. 1.5 MB PDF
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Biographical (Box 1)
    Also available on Reel 1
  - Biographical (Box 5)
  - Biographical (Box 5a)
  - Biographical (Box 21)
  - Charles Abrams: Papers and Files; A Guide to the Microfilm Publication, 1975 (Box 101)
    Annotated with additions and corrections.
  - Nations and Cities: A Comparison of Strategies for Urban Growth, 1970 (Box 101)
  - Description of office files, Undated (Box 101)
  - Bibliographies of reports, articles and speeches, drafts, Undated (Box 101)
  - Examples of schedules, Undated (Box 101)
  - Certificate of Incorporation of Eighth Street Holding Corporation, Inc., Undated (Box 101)
  - Certificate of Incorporation of J & M Operating Corporation, 1958-09-18 (Box 101)
  - Trust Agreement, 1955-04-15 (Box 101)
  - Photographs, Undated (Box 101)
    Mostly portraits
  - Ruth Abrams and miscellaneous materials, Undated (Box 101)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - A-Bl (Box 1)
    Also available on Reel 2
  - Bl-C (Box 2)
  - C (Box 3)
    Also available on Reels 2 and 3
  - D-F (Box 4)
    Also available on Reels 3 and 4
  - G (Box 5)
    Also available on Reel 4
  - H (Box 5a)
  - I-Ka (Box 6)
    Also available on Reels 5 and 6
  - Ka-Ku (Box 7)
  - L-Ma (Box 8)
    Also available on Reel 6
  - Ma-Ne (Box 9)
    Also available on Reels 6 and 7
  - Ne-Po (Box 10)
    Also available on Reels 7 and 8
  - Po-Ry (Box 10a)
  - S-St (Box 11)
  - St-V (Box 12)
    Also available on Reels 8 and 9
  - W-Wo (Box 13)
    Also available on Reels 9 and 10
  - Wo-Z, dated, undated, miscellaneous enclosures (Box 14)
  - Europe travel letters, 1952 (Box 101)
  - London travel letters, 1968 (Box 101)
  - A, Undated (Box 101)
  - B-D, Undated (Box 101)
  - F, Undated (Box 101)
  - Fefferman, Undated (Box 101)
  - Hilbert, Undated (Box 101)
  - G-L, Undated (Box 101)
  - M-N, Undated (Box 102)
  - The Nation/New Leader Controversy, Undated (Box 102)
  - O-P, Undated (Box 102)
  - R-S, Undated (Box 102)
  - Schechter, Arthur, Undated (Box 102)
  - Schulman, John, Undated (Box 102)
  - T-W, Undated (Box 102)
- Series III. Organizations
  - A-C (Box 15)
    Also available on Reels 11 and 12
  - City-Columbia (Box 16)
  - C-D (Box 17)
  - F-H (Box 18)
    Also available on Reel 12
  - Housing and Urban Development-Liberal Party (Box 19)
  - Liberal Party-Mayor's Advisory Council (Box 20)
    Also available on Reels 12 and 13
  - Modern Community Developers-National Association of Real Estate Boards (Box 21)
    Also available on Reels 13 and 14
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing- National Committee on the Housing Emergency (Box 22)
    Also available on Reel 14
  - National Public Housing Conference (Box 23)
    Also available on Reel 15
  - New School for Social Research Correspondence-Lectures (Box 24)
  - New School for Social Research Lectures-New York City Housing Authority (Box 25)
    Also available on Reels 15 and 16
  - New York City Housing Authority-New York State Commission Against Discrimination (Box 26)
    Also available on Reel 16
  - New York State Commission Against Discrimination-New York State Housing and Rent Administration (Box 27)
    Also available on Reel 17
  - New York State Housing and Rent Administration-World Peace through Law (Box 28)
    Also available on Reels 17 and 18
  - American Jewish Congress, 1947 (Box 102)
  - The American City, 1951 (Box 102)
  - American Federation of Housing Authorities, 1939 (Box 102)
  - Anti-Nazi League, 1947 (Box 102)
  - Brighton Beach Design Competition, 1968-05 (Box 102)
  - Chelsea Citizens Project, 1956-1958 (Box 102)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Association, 1963 (Box 102)
  - Citizens' Housing Council of New York, Inc., 1942-1945; 3 Folders (Box 102)
  - Citizens Housing and Planning Council of New York, Inc., 1950 (Box 102)
  - Citizens Union of the City of New York, 1961 (Box 102)
  - City-Wide Citizens Committee on Harlem, 1943-1947 (Box 102)
  - New York City City Council, 1952-1953 (Box 102)
  - Columbia University; Avery Library, Ford Foundation Grant, Institute of Urban Environment, 1964-1968; 14 Folders (Box 103)
    Student strike
  - Council for Civic Unity of San Francisco, Undated (Box 104)
  - Downtown New York Arts Festival, 1968 (Box 104)
  - Greenwich Village, Sih Street zoning, Walter Thabil, 1956-1967; 6 Folders (Box 104)
    Photos
  - International Cooperation Year, 1965 (Box 104)
  - Irish Bilateral Conference, 1968-06-06-1968-06-08 (Box 104)
  - Jefferson Market Courthouse, 1961 (Box 104)
  - Jewish Labor Committee, 1957 (Box 104)
  - Loula D. Lasker Fellowship Trust, 1959-1969; 9 Folders (Box 105)
  - League for Industrial Democracy, 1962-1968 (Box 105)
  - Lectures, 1960-1969 (Box 105)
  - Lehman, Herbert H., 1938 (Box 105)
    Election
  - Liberal Party, 1944-1960; 6 Folders (Box 105)
  - Library of Urban Affairs, 1965-1966 (Box 105)
  - Mayor's Advisory Council, Housing and Redevelopment Subcommittee, 1954; 3 Folders (Box 106)
  - Mayor's Committee for Better Housing, 1954-1955 (Box 106)
  - Mayor's Committee on the Multiple Dwelling Law, 1934-1938 (Box 106)
  - Massachusetts Institute of Technology, 1962 (Box 106)
  - Mutual Real Estate Investment Trust, Modern Community Developers, Planned Communities, 1961-1968 (Box 106)
  - National Association of Housing Officials (NAHO), 1937-1956; 4 Folders (Box 106)
  - National Association of Real Estate Boards, 1941 (Box 106)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing (NCDH), 1955-1968; 12 Folders (Box 107)
  - National Committee Against Discrimination in Housing (NCDH), Trends in Housing, Undated (Box 107)
    Misc. issues
  - National Committee on the Housing Emergency, 1941-1943 (Box 108)
  - National Committee on Housing, 1943-06-23-1947; 8 Folders (Box 108)
  - National Housing Agency, 1943-1945 (Box 108)
  - National Housing Conference, 1952; 3 Folders (Box 108)
    Pictures
  - National Housing Conference, 1952-1962; 10 Folders (Box 109)
  - National Public Housing Conference, 1939-1945; 9 Folders (Box 110)
  - National Public Housing Conference, 1946-1947; 9 Folders (Box 111)
  - New School for Social Research, 1944-1961 (Box 112)
  - New York City Housing Authority, 1937-1960; 3 Folders (Box 112)
  - New York City Housing Authority v. Consolidated Gas, 1936 (Box 112)
  - New York City Housing Authority v Muller, 1935-1936; 4 Folders (Box 112)
  - New York City Housing Authority-First Homes, 1935-1937; 2 Folders (Box 112)
  - New York City Housing Authority-War Housing, 1942 (Box 112)
  - New York State Commission Against Discrimination, 1956-1959; 6 Folders (Box 113)
  - New York State Committee on Discrimination in Housing, 1955, 1959-1960; 2 Folders (Box 113)
  - New York State Joint Legislative Committee to Recodify the Multiple Dwelling Law/on Housing and Multiple Dwellings, 1945-1952; 3 Folders (Box 113)
  - New York State Joint Legislative Committee to Recodify the Multiple Dwelling Law/on Housing and Multiple Dwellings, 1945-1952; 4 Folders (Box 114)
  - New York State Rent Administrator, 1955 (Box 114)
    Letters of Congratulations
  - Omega Chi Fraternity, 1946-1954 (Box 114)
  - Office of Emergency Preparedness, 1964 (Box 114)
  - Planners for Equal Opportunity, Walter Thabit, 1967 (Box 114)
  - Regional Plan Association, 1968 (Box 114)
  - Rent Control, 1937-1962; 5 Folders (Box 114)
  - Seaview Association (Fire Island), 1956 (Box 115)
  - Snag Club, 1960-1963 (Box 115)
  - Socialist Party, 1951 (Box 115)
  - Stockbridge School, 1961-1966 (Box 115)
  - Temporary Committee for Tree Planting Legislation, 1959 (Box 115)
  - Temporary State Housing Rent Commission, 1955 (Box 115)
  - Union for Democratic Action, 1946 (Box 115)
  - United Nations, Undated (Box 115)
  - United States Housing Authority, 1937 (Box 115)
  - Urban Redevelopment, 1949-1953 (Box 115)
  - World Bank, 1966 (Box 115)
  - World Study Tours, 1945-1950 (Box 115)
  - Europe travel letters, 1948 (Box 115)
  - Germany travel letters, 1948-07 (Box 115)
  - Europe travel letters, 1950 (Box 115)
- Series IV. Studies
  - Alaska-Baltimore (Box 29)
    Also available on Reel 19
  - Barbados-Bolivia (Box 30)
  - Boston-Calcutta (Box 31)
    Also available on Reel 20
  - California (Box 32)
  - California (Box 33)
  - California-Chile (Box 34)
    Also available on Reels 20 and 21
  - Ghana [Gold Coast] (Box 35)
    Also available on Reel 21
  - Ghana-Ireland (Box 36)
    Also available on Reels 21 and 22
  - Jamaica-Louisville (Box 37)
    Also available on Reel 22
  - New York City Housing Task Force (Box 38)
    Also available on Reel 23
  - Nigeria (Box 39)
  - Pakistan-Philadelphia (Box 40)
    Also available on Reels 23 and 24
  - Philippines-Singapore (Box 41)
    Also available on Reel 24
  - Turkey-Venezuela (Box 42)
    Also available on Reel 25
  - "Housing the Alaska Native.", Undated (Box 116)
    Including appendices
    >Alaska
  - Memorandum to the Concept Team on the Unrescathed Political Issues, Undated (Box 116)
    >Baltimore
  - Involving the Baltimore Highway, Undated (Box 116)
  - Memorandum to the Concept Team on Housing Policy, Undated (Box 116)
  - Memorandum to Norman Klein on Proposals for Stabilizing Rosemont, Undated (Box 116)
  - Trip Diary, 1967 (Box 116)
    >Calcutta
  - Summary of Housing in California, 1963-03-11 (Box 116)
    A condensation with illustrations
    >California
  - "Housing and Community Facilities," Committee 3, pp. 3-1 to 3-18 in Reports of Committees of Special Areas of Work. Supplement to Review Report Number 1, 1960-09-10 (Box 116)
    >Japan
  - "Report of Housing and Urban Renewal Task Force,", 1966-01-10 (Box 116)
    >New York
  - "The Negro Housing Problem: A Program for Philadelphia,", 1966-09-1966-12; 5 Folders (Box 116)
    >Philadelphia
  - Trip Diary, 1954-1959 (Box 116)
    Correspondence and Memorandum
    >Turkey
  - Photographs and slides, Undated (Box 117)
    Ethiopia, Alaska, Ghana, Bolivia, Japan, Chile, Madagasca
- Series V. Articles and Speeches
  - 1935-1945 (Box 43)
    Also available on Reel 26
  - 1946-1947 (Box 44)
    Also available on Reels 26 and 27
  - 1948-1949 (Box 45)
    Also available on Reel 27
  - 1950 (Box 46)
    Also available on Reels 27 and 28
  - 1951 (Box 47)
    Also available on Reel 28
  - 1952 (Box 48)
    Also available on Reels 28 and 29
  - 1953-January 1954 (Box 49)
    Also available on Reels 29 and 30
  - February-October 1954 (Box 50)
    Also available on Reel 30
  - 1955 (Box 51)
  - 1955-1956 (Box 52)
  - 1956-57 (Box 53)
    Also available on Reels 30 and 31
  - 1958-1959 (Box 54)
    Also available on Reel 31
  - 1960 (Box 55)
    Also available on Reel 32
  - 1961-1962 (Box 56)
  - 1963-1964 (Box 57)
    Also available on Reel 32 and 33
  - 1965 (Box 58)
    Also available on Reel 33
  - 1966-1967 (Box 59)
    Also available on Reels 33 and 34
  - 1967-1968 (Box 60)
    Also available on Reel 34
  - 1969-undated and untitled (Box 61)
  - Speaking Requests Refused, 1946-1949 (Box 62)
    Also available on Reel 35
  - New York Post(scrapbooks) (Box 63)
  - New York Post Correspondence (Box 64)
  - Panel. "The People vs. H. C. L." Consumers National Federation, 1937-12-11 (Box 118)
  - "Brief of Amicus Curiae." Anna M. Dornan v. The Philadelphia Housing Authority, A Corporation, et al. In the Supreme Court of Pennsylvania, Eastern District, January term., 1938 (Box 118)
  - "Housing Opposition: New Style." The Nation, 1938-12-24 (Box 118)
  - "Slum Clearance or Vacant Land Development?" Shelter, 1939-02 (Box 118)
  - Reprinted in The Reference Shelf, 1939 (Box 118)
  - "Housing and Politics." Survey Graphic, 29, no. 2, 1940-02 (Box 118)
  - Preliminary Report of the Legislative Committee to the Temporary National Committee on Housing Legislation, 1941-01-24 (Box 118)
  - Speech. Convention of the National Public Housing Conference, St. Louis, 1944-03-24 (Box 118)
  - "Economic Changes in Real Estate." In New Architecture and City Planning: A Symposium, edited by Paul Zucker. New York: Philosophical Library., 1944 (Box 118)
  - The No Man's Land in Housing." Citizens' Housing Council of New York, 1945-03-15 (Box 118)
  - The Walls of Stuy vesant Town. The Nation, 1945-03-24 (Box 118)
  - "Shall We Spend More Money for Public Housing?" Central Harlem Council for Community Planning, YMCA, 1945-10-30 (Box 118)
  - "Housing Hoax?: A Criticism of the GI Bill of Rights." Veterans Outlook, 1945-10 (Box 118)
  - Progressives and the Social Order-Here and Abroad. Annual Conference, League for Industrial Democracy, 1946-02-08 (Box 118)
    Panel
  - "Joseph Dorsey, etal. v. Stuyvesant Town Corporation and Metropolitan Life Insurance Company." Supreme Court of the State of New York, 1947-07-09 (Box 118)
    Brief of Plaintiffs
  - New York Metropolitan Committee for Planning, 1948-12-16 (Box 118)
    Speech, See February 1949
  - Progressive Architecture, 1948-12-17 (Box 118)
    Article
  - Housing: The Ever-Recurring Crisis. In Saving American Capitalism, edited by Seymour E. Harris. New York: Knopf., Undated (Box 118)
  - Community Relations Seminar on Fair Housing Practices, 1949-01-12 (Box 118)
    Speech
  - How Good is 'Best' Under Title 608? Progressive Architecture, 1949-02 (Box 118)
  - The Role of the President of the United States in Housing and Civil Rights." National Conference on Constitutional Rights and American Freedom, 1950-10-11-1950-10-12 (Box 118)
    Excerpts
  - The New 'Gresham's Law of Neighborhoods': Fact or Fiction? Appraisal Journal vol. 19, no. 3, 1951-07 (Box 118)
    Reprinted in Selected Readings in Real Estate Appraisal. Chicago: Lakeside Press, 1954, and in The Changing Metropolis, edited by Frederick I. Tietze ano James L. McKeown, 71-76. Boston: Houghton Mifflin, 1964.
  - This I Believe., 1952-02-19 (Box 118)
  - Government Administration Seminar, Columbia University, 1952-03-28 (Box 118)
    Lecture
  - Urban Land Policies. International Federation for Housing and Planning, 1952-09-22 (Box 118)
    >Lisbon
  - United Israel Appeal, 1952-11-09 (Box 118)
  - Speech. National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials, Washington, D. C, 1952-11-13 (Box 118)
    See editorial, "Right End, Wrong Means," Minneapolis Slur, November 21 and CA letter to the Editor, December 1
  - Private Home Building and Ownership for Minorities: Fiction or Reality?" Mayor's Council on Human Relations, Minneapolis, 1952-11-20 (Box 118)
  - Statement in Acceptance of the 1953 Award from the League for Industrial Democracy, 1953-02-08 (Box 118)
    Including "Extemporaneous Remarks"
  - Criticism of Abrams' work on Puerto Rico, 1953-02-09 (Box 118)
  - "Facing the Housing Problem." The Wesley Foundation, 1953-03-08 (Box 118)
    Harvard University
    >Cambridge
  - "Land Policies and Effect on Development Possibilities." Bemis Foundation Conference on Economic Development and Housing Abroad, 1953-05-01 (Box 118)
    See September 22,1952
  - 1953-06-08 (Box 118)
  - Opinion of Referee, 1954-05-05 (Box 119)
    See full entry under June 8,1953
  - 23rd Annual National Housing Conference, 1954-06-07 (Box 119)
    Speech, Entered in The Congressional Record Appendix, June 25
    >Washington, D.C.
  - "Urban Land Problems and Policies," Housing and Town and Country Planning. Bulletin No. 7, 1954-06-17 (Box 119)
    New York: Housing and Town and Country Planning Section of the Department of Social Affairs, United Nations. Abrams was guest editor and wrote the lead article
  - Pacific Northwest Regional Council, National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, 1954-07-16 (Box 119)
  - Women's Club of New York, 1955-02-17 (Box 120)
  - Annual Legislative Conference, Liberal Party, 1955-02-21 (Box 120)
    >Albany
  - "Will Your Rent Go up?" Housing Committee of the Lower East Side Planning Council, 1955-02-24 (Box 120)
  - "Slums and Our Children." New York Herald Tribune Fresh Air Fund, 1955-03-19 (Box 120)
  - "Memorandum on the Washington Square Southeast Development Plan." Hearing, Subcommittee No. 2, Select Committee on Small Business, House of Representatives, 84th Congress, 1955-04-19 (Box 120)
  - Potomac Chapter. National Association of Housing and Redevelopment Officials, 1955-05-04 (Box 120)
    Speech, see NAHRO Newsletter June 15
  - Review of Adventures of a Slum Fighter, by Charles F. Palmer. New York Times, 1955-10-18 (Box 120)
    Actually published November 6
  - "A Regional Approach to the Housing Problem." Conference on Technology for Israel and the Middle East, 1955-11-01 (Box 120)
    Submitted to Yearbook Technion, September 16
  - "Income and Ability to Pay for Housing of Nonwhite Families in New York State." Report of the Commission on Housing and Family Life to the National Association of Intergroup Relations Officials., Undated (Box 120)
  - Trade Union Council of the Liberal Party, 1956-03-21 (Box 120)
  - National Housing Conference, 1956-04-12 (Box 120)
    Speech, printed in Progressive Architecture (August)
  - "Redevelopment: Its Hazards and Opportunities." Conference on Housing, Allegheny County Council on Civil Rights, 1956-04-28 (Box 120)
    >Pittsburgh
  - "Civil Rights in 1956: Politics Replaces the Economic Motive.' Commentary, 1956-08 (Box 120)
  - Milton Steinberg Group of Hadassah, 1956-09-24 (Box 120)
  - New York State Welfare Conference, 1956-12-11 (Box 120)